Francisco Tobar

Computer Science Engineer

Skills

Coding C/C++, Python, Ruby, Bash, SQL.

Machine Learning TensorFlow, PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-learn, R.& Data Science

Software Ruby On Rails, Django, HTML5, JavaScript, Git, PHP. **Development**

IT Operations GNU/Linux, Apache, Nginx, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, PHP.

Research

Mar 2018-ongoing Overcoming the memory limitations in Image Generating GANs,

Advisor: Claudio Torres.

Research focused in reducing the computational cost of training image generating GANs without sacrificing the quality of results through multi-frequency separations of feature maps, achieving a reduction of approximately 30% of memory usage without affecting the quality of the results. https://github.com/ftobarm/tob-GAN

Work Experience

Mar 2018 Jun 2018 **Software Development**, *Dlogistic*, Valparaíso.

Package management web application for delivery using smartphone as barcode readers to assign packages to different drivers.

Mar 2017 to Nov **Software Development**, *Zoome*, Valparaíso.

2017 Al based software for image capturing with lights automatization and edition of photos for e-commerce. Project Webpage: https://www.facebook.com/76Zoome/

Jan 2017 to Feb 2017 Data Scientist, U-Planner, Valparaíso, Internship.

Development of a Machine Learning algorithm for course enrollment prediction for educational institutions.

Jan 2016 to Feb 2016 **Data Scientist**, *Geoinova*, Santiago, Internship.

Development of a quick implementation of K-neighbors in high dimension and implementation of communication between Cuda DLLs and Electron Framework

Education

2017-current Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María, Valparaíso, Chile,

Msc. in Computer Engineering.

2013–2019 Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María, Valparaíso, Chile,

Bsc. and Professional degree in Informatics Engineering.

Languages

Spanish	Native	
English	Advanced	TOEIC Score 915

Teaching Assistant

2018	Computer Networks, 1 semester, UTFSM.
2016-2018	Operating Systems , 3 semesters, UTFSM.
2017	Computational Statistics, 1 semester, UTFSM.
2016	$\textbf{Algorithms and Complexity} \ , \ 1 \ semester, \ UTFSM.$
2016-2017	Computer Architecture, 2 semesters, UTFSM.
2016	Discrete mathematics, 1 semester, UTFSM.
2014	Computer programming, 1 semeste, UTFSM.